<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Austin Willis</title>
  <subtitle>Posts about things I&#39;m tinkering with or thinking about.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://austinwillis.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://austinwillis.com/" />
  <updated>2024-12-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://austinwillis.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Austin Willis</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Textpod</title>
    <link href="https://austinwillis.com/blog/textpod/" />
    <updated>2024-12-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://austinwillis.com/blog/textpod/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;oracle&quot;&gt;Oracle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made a free account for oracle cloud. Provisioned a linux instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;docker&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update package manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo yum update
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;yum-utils&lt;/code&gt; and docker repo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo dnf install -y dnf-utils zip unzip
dnf config-manager --add-repo=https://download.docker.com/linux/centos/docker-ce.repo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Docker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;dnf remove -y runc
dnf install -y docker-ce --nobest
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gave up getting docker on oracle cloud free machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to just install textpod with cargo instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Cargo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl https://sh.rustup.rs -sSf | sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install textpod:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cargo install textpod
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The free machine is just too slow. Got a E3.Flex instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made sure routing was working for apache: https://docs.oracle.com/en/learn/lab_compute_instance/index.html#troubleshooting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installing docker this time. :pray:
https://oracle-base.com/articles/linux/docker-install-docker-on-oracle-linux-ol8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok working, used this nginx reverse proxy thing to route a subdomain: https://github.com/nginx-proxy/nginx-proxy?tab=readme-ov-file
Not sure if I did that right but it works for http://notes.austinwillis.com to go to the textpod container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ooooh, nice: http://worknotes.austinwillis.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started another container of textpod:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo docker run --detach --rm --name textpod2 -d -v $(pwd)/notes:/app -p 8081:3000 --env VIRTUAL_HOST=worknotes.austinwillis.com freetonik/textpod
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This routes the other subdomain to a differnt notes server with a new file.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On Sharing</title>
    <link href="https://austinwillis.com/blog/sharing/" />
    <updated>2024-11-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://austinwillis.com/blog/sharing/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[Commentary on]: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.elenarossini.com/a-new-way-to-describe-the-fediverse-and-its-opposition-to-big-tech/?ref=selfh.st&quot;&gt;A new way to describe the Fediverse and its opposition to Big Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wathcing the Macy&#39;s thanksgiving day parade had me considering the commercialization of holiday giving. I was struck with an interaction I had the other day. We just moved to NYC and all of our belongings are currently stored in a NJ warehouse. On the day before Thanksgiving I took a trip to the warehouse to pick up a few things which our moving company charges a small fee to do. I was happy to pay it, but when asking the mover how I should pay, he simply said &amp;quot;Happy holidays&amp;quot; and gestured to not worry about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have financialized almost all aspects of society in the last ~century~ or so, we have also lost something else that used to be paramount to our social sphere. We now completely seperate our financial and social relationships. This is great for many aspects of society. Credit access is no longer contingent on social standing or class of birth. It (~somewhat~) effectively removes racial discrimination in economic transactions. But we also lose an important connection to our community. We no longer have opportunities to show kindness to our neighbors without expectation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gift giving in American society has become sullied pretty throughly with a sense of competition. Giving a gift ascribes a level of indebtedness to the recipient and not reciprocating with a gift of equal value is an affront.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that long ago, the indebtedness to our neghbors was a ~real phenomenom~. We bought from the grocer on credit. The butcher. The banker. Each transation you made was likely putting you in debt to the people surrounding you. This became a problem when you couldn&#39;t pay back since your social sphere collapsed as a result of financial challenges. You may have also performed barter, even if not necessary it may be convenient. The butcher may pay the grocer with product rather than cash because they are likely awaiting payment from their customers. This kind of arangement provides a convenient avenue for community building. &amp;quot;Happy holidays&amp;quot;. Today we call this &amp;quot;mutual aid&amp;quot; and have industrialized the concept of giving money away. Without a consistent mechanism of equal value trade, we instead create an expectation of it where it is meant to be an ~inequal~ trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;big-tech-big-food&quot;&gt;Big Tech &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; Big Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do really appreciate this analogy of Big Tech &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; Big Food. We have centralized and financialized our social interactions to an absolute extreme. In the last few years, I have really made an effort to improve my cooking skills. I think I&#39;ve become somewhat good at it. It takes practice. But I&#39;m someone who likes challenges, likes making a system, gernally has the perseverence (or sheer stubbornness) to become determined to do something well. Not everyone is like that, or at least not with all things. This is why we must share. Unforuntately, we have become ~very bad~ at building communities around who is good at what and who we &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to share with. It&#39;s much easier to just get paid for the 1 thing you are good at and buy everything else. Like social engagement. This is the opportunity for the fediverse. Some of us are &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; at running websites. We can share that with others and prevent them from &lt;em&gt;needing&lt;/em&gt; to consume nothing but junk &lt;s&gt;food&lt;/s&gt; websites. Just like food, some families lack a cook. This used to be solved primarily by the multi-genreational household, but American consumerism has succesfully destroyed that institution of society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is on my TODO list this next year...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cook for more people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide technology for people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe that is a narrative that works for people... Somewhere to find meaning. But it has to become something people &lt;em&gt;know they want&lt;/em&gt; and the junk food analogy is a great way to convince them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Self Hosting</title>
    <link href="https://austinwillis.com/blog/self-hosting/" />
    <updated>2024-11-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://austinwillis.com/blog/self-hosting/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a collection of tools I am interested in running. I will try and post an update for each one as I get them going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;read-later&quot;&gt;Read Later&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wallabag.org/&quot;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://readeck.org/en/?ref=selfh.st&quot;&gt;ReadDeck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;feed-reader&quot;&gt;Feed Reader&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freshrss.org/&quot;&gt;FreshRSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;location&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://owntracks.org/&quot;&gt;OwnTracks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://noted.lol/install-joplin-server-using-docker-compose/&quot;&gt;Joplin&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/freetonik/textpod?ref=selfh.st&quot;&gt;Textpod&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;writing&quot;&gt;Writing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://writefreely.org/?ref=selfh.st&quot;&gt;WriteFreely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;search&quot;&gt;Search&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SecureAI-Tools/SecureAI-Tools/&quot;&gt;SecureAI-Tools&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.paperless-ngx.com/&quot;&gt;Paperless-ngx&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ItzCrazyKns/Perplexica&quot;&gt;Perplexica&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.hoarder.app/&quot;&gt;Hoarder&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/searxng/searxng&quot;&gt;SearXNG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://olares.medium.com/building-a-local-perplexity-alternative-with-perplexica-ollama-and-searxng-71602523e256&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What do you do after a layoff?</title>
    <link href="https://austinwillis.com/blog/layoffs/" />
    <updated>2024-11-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://austinwillis.com/blog/layoffs/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-follow-orders&quot;&gt;1. Follow orders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically do nothing. Learn who your new manager is. Say hello nice to meet you. What do I do now. Then just do that. I don&#39;t blame anyone. Rent to pay. Mouths to feed. We all know you can end up on the street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe that&#39;s what I&#39;ll do. Just &#39;rest and vest&#39;-ish, but not rest too much cause maybe working &#39;hard&#39; acutally matters. Doesn&#39;t seem to entirely. I don&#39;t know if I necessarily work hard but I&#39;m proud of my work. Honestly if I put a number of hours on it, I&#39;m a little embarrased. Like pretty low. I&#39;m honestly kind of spoiled most of the time. But I have worked long hours this year. Oncall overnight babysitting a dashboard, trying ranom little tweaks to get something unstuck. That was a while ago and I have slacked off a bit lately. My partner has been upset at me during these times because of working too much. I&#39;ve sacrificed family for work, which feels even worse when you see how little it actually matters. How little your work really means to the people making decicisions that could derail your entire life. I genuinely like to help our customers get stuff done, and have seen positive feedback from customers directly on my work. But what am I really getting out of that? Even though I can find purpose in doing things like this, I don&#39;t really &#39;own&#39; the results. No matter how well they pay me, or how many &#39;kudos&#39; or promotions are handed out, it&#39;s ultimately not &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; customer but the corporations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-be-an-opportunist&quot;&gt;2. Be an opportunist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do yoy have ideas about how the workplace should operate? People are gone and there are now possibly less people between you and power. Know a manager who you could get a call with? Think they could be receptive to your ideas? Have no shame?
There are incentive structures that I do not trust. Lines that maybe can&#39;t be crossed. A dogma...ideology...philosophy...culture? One that I&#39;m not sure I belong to. Maybe I&#39;m wrong, we can&#39;t do things any way other than the direction everyone else is going. How honest are the calls for &#39;every idea is on the table&#39;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I already I am already an opportunist. I&#39;ve been around through other layoffs and I&#39;m still here. There are people that have climbed the ladder through attrition and there are definitely opportunities that those relationships provided me as power was redistributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-organize&quot;&gt;3. Organize&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we organize collectively to take power over our workplace? This will not be easy. It will be a fight. It will be uncomfortable. We have to have uncomfortable conversations. That&#39;s the nature of the resource bargain. It&#39;s easy to understand how any power someone gains is used to protect themselves in the heirarchy rather than to share it. This whole system is designed from the beginning as a strict hierarchy. Is there any possiblity to dilute it, or does it have to be completely destroyed? Could the organization even survive without it at this point? How do you even start organizing in an organization like this? Striking doesn&#39;t really hit the bottom line. Layoffs are possible because the product continues to print money without any work being done. Maybe we are just doomed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But maybe that means there is nothing to lose by trying... It has started to feel like the writing is on the wall. How big will the layoffs be when the next hype bubble bursts? Is the work we&#39;re doing now just preparing for the end of our own jobs? Any improvement in reliability just creating an opportunity for your job to become obsolete?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>